Miles Johan Bailey-Braendgaard, Software Engineer

Oxford, United Kingdom, +447391894290, milesbb101@gmail.com

Nationality	UK, Denmark (EU), and US				
LINKS	Portfolio, LinkedIn, Github				
PROFILE	Software Engineer with a background in computer science, biomechanics, arts, and engineering who is ready to develop, learn, and become a proactive member of your team.				
	Have experience adapting to new languages, IDE's, and technologies and applying them to cross-disciplinary problems. Technologies I often work with include: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, AWS (S3, Lambda, ECS, and others), React.js, Node.js, CSS, HTML, MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redux, Three.js, Bootstrap, Git/Github/Gitlabs, Vercel, Netlify, JIRA, Confluence, Teams, Agile Methodology.				
EXPERIENCE					
Jan 2023 — Present	Junior Software Engineer, Aurora Energy Research	Oxford, UK			
	 Full-stack responsibilities within a complex architecture of event-driven serverless Typescript and Python based micro-services and seamless React micro-frontends using MySQL and AWS Cloud services including Lambda, S3, and ECS 				
	 Developing fintech SaaS/MaaS (Modelling-as-a-Service) software solutions that handle bulk data and deliver bespoke financial simulations and analysis to worldwide internal and external users. Based in (Oxford) head office Software Engineering department often working inter-disciplinarily with analysts, modellers, and product leads 				
	 Often work with commercial and other similar departments and help explain and relate deeper technical concepts in our architecture which they may not be as familiar with to the company's business logic/goals 				
Nov 2021 — Jan 2022	Intern Prosthetist/Orthotist, Aktiv Ortopedteknik	Lund, Sweden			
	 Clinical placement working hands-on with patients and collaborating in multidisciplinary teams within Skåne University-Hosptial. Experience handling delicate scenarios and design problems under time pressure including biohazard scenarios, war-related injuries, language interpretation, and healthcare work during the COVID-19 pandemic Adapted quickly to new patient records databases and software, gained in-depth experience including with Upper Limb Prosthetics. 				
Aug 2020 — Aug 2021	Writer, EDIT Newspaper	Jönköping, Sweden			
	 Wrote English and Swedish language articles on topics such as politics, social issues, and art for both the physical and online editions of the Jönköping University student newspaper. 				
Sep 2019 — Jun 2021	International Student Union Rep., Jönköping Student Union	Jönköping, Sweden			
	 Representative for the School of Medicine Student Union and member of the Integration and Activity Committee organising events, trips, and support for international students in Sweden 				
May 2019 — Dec 2019	Software Developer, Culture Hustle	Bournemouth, UK			
	 Developed an AI 'Chatbot' (Primarily in AIML 2.0, HTML, and JavaScript) for the company to aid in marketing and customer support and UX. 				
Mar 2019 — Jun 2019	Production Assistant, Culture Hustle	Bournemouth, UK			
	• Assistant to British artist, creator, and activist Stuart Semple in both manufacture of commercial art supply products and maintenance of art studio space.				
Jun 2015	Software Engineering Work Experience, Siemens Traffic Solutions	Poole, UK			

• Shadowed software engineering department whilst learning about and designing junction traffic sorting algorithms in C#.

EDUCATION					
Jun 2022 — Dec 2022	Full Stack Web Developer Program, EPICODE/Strive School			Remote	
	 High-intensive highly-rated Full-Stack Development Bootcamp (Formerly known as Strive School) focusing on MERN and PERN stack including topics such as Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL, Cryptography, and Authentication. 				
Aug 2019 — Jun 2022	BSc Prosthetics an	d Orthotics, Jönköping U	Jönköping, Sweder		
	 International Society of Prosthetics and Orthotics (ISPO) Accredited Program Clinical, tech, and research focused including modules on statistics Dissertation on the application, accuracy, and reliability of 3D scanning devices and spatial data processing software in the field 				
Jul 2017	UNIQ Oxford Un	UNIQ Oxford University Summer School			
	$ \bullet Official summer school run by the university with specialisation in Engineering and Engineering software including MATLAB and C++ \\$				
Sep 2014 — Jul 2018	A-Levels and GCS	Es, Poole Grammar Schoo	ol	Poole, UK	
		ns, Electronics, and German ding Maths, Further Maths, Con	mputer Science, and E	Electronics	
AWARDS					
Jul 2016	Arkwright Engineering Scholarship				
	• Competitive UK-based scholarship sponsoring school and extra-curricular projects in Engineering, Computing, and Technical Design, including a placement at UK-based defence firm Ultra Electronics.				
SKILLS	 I work daily with Typescript and Python though I have some experience with C# and Solidity and would be able to quickly learn and adapt to other languages/frameworks/cloud services as required Experience with 3D modelling, scanning, printing, and gait analysis software including Canfit, Paromed, Autodesk, Vxelements, Visual3D, and Qualisys People- and detail-oriented, with experience organising and hosting events, trips, and student support in the Jönköping University Student Union and at work 				
LANGUAGES	English	Native speaker	Danish	Highly proficient	
	Swedish	Highly proficient	German	Good working knowledge	
HOBBIES	Languages - trying desperately to learn Mandarin; Music - play the bass and piano; Hiking - every other weekend;				